<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>AstroGrid registry installation</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
    <section name="Installation">
    <p>
    <i>Definition 'Context Name' - is your webapp name (hence usually the unpacked directory name in the webapps).  This will be used
a lot in various registry documentation usually with curly brackets.</i>
    </p>    
      <p>
         The installations below have mainly been tested on tomcat versions 5.0.19-5.0.28 java1.4, 5.5.17-5.5.19 with java.1.5.  But the "Manual Installation" could be carried out on 
 other servlet/j2ee containers and would welcome success or failure stories relating to other containers.  <br />For the purpose of most instructions here the guide will refer to tomcat.<br />
        <br />
        <i><b>Note:</b>tomcat 5.0 users using java1.5 has been done and requires a system property to be set:<br />
        javax.xml.transform.TransformerFactory=com.sun.org.apache.xalan.internal.xsltc.trax.TransformerFactoryImpl<br />
        </i>
		<strong>Be sure to read the bottom section if you know your deploying this in a servlet container that will "NOT" unpack the war file.</strong><br />
		Unpacking is usually a term of unzipping/extracting the war and is something typical that tomcat does when deploying a war file.
      <br />
      Download Location of war: http://developer.astrogrid.org
      </p>
      <subsection name="Installation">
      <p>
         Most of the work is in the configure page, for installation. 
         <ul>
            <li>Take the war file and rename it to something you prefer e.g. registry.war (be sure to keep the .war ending).  Typical names are "astrogrid-registry.war" or "registry.war"</li>
            <li>Go to your Tomcat manager e.g. http://localhost:8080/manager/html (this may ask for a username and password ask your admin or check {tomcat}/conf/tomcat-users.xml for a user with the role of manager)</li>
            <li>If you do not have access to Tomcat manager because it is restricted on your server you may also copy the war file into the {tomcat}/webapps directory to install.</li>
            <li>Tomcat by default should unpack the war file into a directory in that webapps directory.  
                Directory Name should be the same as the war file minus the ".war" part.</li>			
            <li><strong>You should be done (for the installation part now for Configure) you should be able to access the url: http://{server}:{port}/{context} (optionally you can also check the webapps for a directory to verify).</strong></li>
            <li>The Configure will be on the menu at the left hand side of your Registry web application.</li>
            <li>If it does not unpack it then you may have it turned off in your tomcat or your using a different servlet container that does not unpack the war files "see bottom section if you know it does not unpack wars".</li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      </subsection>      
	  <subsection name="Handling Packed wars">
		<p>This section is for servlet containers that do not unpack the war file.  You may be able go to your
		Registry but it cannot make a connection to the embedded database.  You must download an empty eXist that can
		be unzipped, and like the above directions go to your Configure page in the Registry to set your property to this new location of the
		database. SEE THE 3RD POINT BELOW to set a property to your database.
			<ul>
			  <li>Download an empty eXist db zip located at: <a href='http://software.astrogrid.org/eXist/empty_exist_for_internal_registry.zip'>Registry eXist Zip</a></li>
			  <li>Now unzip it in some directory where you want your database.</li>
			  <li>Now a property must be set "reg.custom.exist.configuration" property and point to this directory plus conf.xml ex: /exist/db/conf.xml.</li>
			  <li>Information on changing properties is in the Configure section.</li>
			</ul>
		</p>
	  </subsection>
    </section>
   </body>
</document>